It contains multiple registries. Right now, this registration contract is online for a lot of these chains.
它包含多个注册表。目前，许多此类连锁店的注册合同都已在线。
And later on, this reputation validation system will also be online to help these users to really validate and give reputation on different agents.
稍后，这个信誉验证系统也将上线，帮助这些用户真正验证并给予不同代理的信誉。
If you really want to check out what's online and what's on-chain for the different agents, feel free to check out this 8004scan.io.
如果您确实想了解不同代理的在线情况和链上情况，请随时查看 8004scan.io。
Beyond that, as we can see, we already support most of the chains, and at the same time, we can see different chains that have different types of agents.
除此之外，正如我们所看到的，我们已经支持大多数链，同时我们可以看到不同的链具有不同类型的代理。
Some agents do this DeFi trading, and some of them do this kind of portfolio management. Some of them do this yield farming across different chains.
有些代理做这种 DeFi 交易，有些代理做这种投资组合管理。他们中的一些人在不同的链条上进行这种流动性耕作。
And the growth is pretty fast across all different chains.
所有不同连锁店的增长都非常快。
At the same time, as Austin in the morning mentioned about, he created these easy skills. It covers Ethereum and different L2s.
同时，正如奥斯汀早上提到的，他创造了这些简单的技能。它涵盖了以太坊和不同的 L2。
Beyond that, we found that for a lot of the agents on this 8004scan, they probably want something extra.
除此之外，我们发现对于这个 8004scan 上的许多代理来说，他们可能想要一些额外的东西。
For example, they also want to know the knowledge of the chain itself, the protocol itself, and they also want to further know all the different endpoints for different DeFi protocols.
例如，他们还想了解链本身、协议本身的知识，还想进一步了解不同 DeFi 协议的所有不同端点。
And typically, some DeFi protocols have different contract deployment on different chains.
通常，一些 DeFi 协议在不同的链上有不同的合约部署。
To provide very accurate information, we also developed this CryptoSkill.org.
为了提供非常准确的信息，我们还开发了 CryptoSkill.org。
It indexes all the crypto and blockchain information, not just on-chain, not just all the DAX.
它索引所有加密货币和区块链信息，而不仅仅是链上信息，不仅仅是所有 DAX。
It also supports a bunch of the CEX and all the necessary information for different blockchain builders, crypto builders, and all traders.
它还支持大量 CEX 以及不同区块链构建者、加密货币构建者和所有交易者的所有必要信息。
Beyond that, as I mentioned, after all these learnings and practices, we figured that just providing this information and doing the engineering ourselves is not enough.
除此之外，正如我提到的，经过所有这些学习和实践，我们认为仅仅提供这些信息并自己进行工程设计是不够的。
And it's better, based on our experience, to provide some tools for blockchain builders in general.
根据我们的经验，最好为一般的区块链构建者提供一些工具。
So that's why we built a complete engineering suite for all the developers who are using this web coding and engineering.
这就是为什么我们为所有使用此 Web 编码和工程的开发人员构建了完整的工程套件。
It includes a very fine-tuned, not just one, multiple fine-tuned models we call AltLM.
它包括一个非常微调的模型，而不仅仅是一个，我们称之为 AltLM 的多个微调模型。
Right now you can visit altlm.ai and you can choose different models, and the model itself has all the necessary information of crypto and blockchain.
现在你可以访问altlm.ai，你可以选择不同的模型，模型本身拥有加密货币和区块链的所有必要信息。
So then in that case, you don't really need to import extra MCP skills.
那么在这种情况下，你真的不需要导入额外的 MCP 技能。
You can just call the models and then you can get what you want from these blockchain and crypto.
你只需调用模型，然后你就可以从这些区块链和加密货币中获得你想要的东西。
And beyond that, I know a lot of these developers, they prefer CLI, all these kind of terminals, instead of this website or chat box.
除此之外，我认识很多这样的开发人员，他们更喜欢 CLI，所有这些类型的终端，而不是这个网站或聊天框。
So we also built another CLI called AltCode.
所以我们还构建了另一个名为 AltCode 的 CLI。
Based on the benchmark from Cloud Code and Codex, Alice did rank AltCode even better than Cloud Code and also this Codex CLI.
根据 Cloud Code 和 Codex 的基准，Alice 确实将 AltCode 评为比 Cloud Code 和 Codex CLI 更好的。
And beyond that, we have another product called CloudCrawl.
除此之外，我们还有另一个产品，称为 CloudCrawl。
And we empower all different agents and hosted on-chain and also on the cloud.
我们为所有不同的代理提供支持，并在链上和云上托管。
So you can just click once and then you can have the agent to do all the different tasks for you.
因此，您只需单击一次，然后就可以让代理为您完成所有不同的任务。
And I just mentioned, for normal users, you can just use this RM.
我刚才提到，对于普通用户来说，你可以使用这个RM。
It has the chat box, you can just click and go through and right now it has some welcome gifts.
它有聊天框，你只需点击即可浏览，现在它还有一些欢迎礼物。
If you want some extra credits, you can go to our booth and our team members will give you some extra credits to use it.
如果您想要一些额外的积分，您可以到我们的展位，我们的团队成员会给您一些额外的积分来使用。
Beyond that, it has all different MCP tools already embedded into the models.
除此之外，它还已将所有不同的 MCP 工具嵌入到模型中。
So you can directly use it to code whatever, for example, do the engineering for the Ethereum core protocol.
所以你可以直接用它来编写任何代码，例如，为以太坊核心协议进行工程​​。
Beyond that, it's self-learning, self-evolving protocol.
除此之外，它是自学习、自进化的协议。
And we're automatically learning and creating new skills for blockchains and crypto.
我们正在自动学习和创造区块链和加密货币的新技能。
And beyond that, it has all different types of models.
除此之外，它还有各种不同类型的模型。
You can use these models for different tasks.
您可以将这些模型用于不同的任务。
For example, you can use a basic model for this kind of normal checking.
例如，您可以使用基本模型来进行这种正常检查。
You can also use some other models for coding all these more complex tasks.
您还可以使用一些其他模型来编码所有这些更复杂的任务。
And beyond that, as I mentioned, if you are these kind of expert developers or senior engineers,
除此之外，正如我提到的，如果您是这些专家开发人员或高级工程师，
you can just use Oracle CLI to enjoy this crypto-native coding experience.
您只需使用 Oracle CLI 即可享受这种加密原生编码体验。
And beyond that, if you want to try out these crypto-native agents,
除此之外，如果您想尝试这些加密原生代理，
you can also visit the website and launch the agent just by a few clicks.
您还可以访问该网站并只需单击几下即可启动代理。
And I share a lot of things.
我分享了很多东西。
You can just quickly check out various different websites.
您可以快速查看各种不同的网站。
But my point is that we are already at the beginning of this agentic era.
但我的观点是，我们已经处于这个代理时代的开始。
And for most of the time in the future, it's not like whether you are sort of powerful enough.
而且在未来的大部分时间里，问题并不在于你是否足够强大。
For most of the time, it's like whether you can leverage the AI or different tools to make yourself more powerful enough.
大多数时候，这就像你是否可以利用人工智能或不同的工具来让自己变得足够强大。
And as I mentioned, agent is not the master. You are the master.
正如我所提到的，代理人不是主人。你是主人。
And the AI is just the tools.
人工智能只是工具。
You should figure out how to use these AI tools to empower yourself to be a much bigger person
你应该弄清楚如何使用这些人工智能工具来让自己成为一个更伟大的人
and to really enjoy this agentic era in the future.
并在未来真正享受这个代理时代。
That's all my sharing. Thanks, everyone.
这就是我的全部分享了。谢谢大家。
Thank you, YQ.
谢谢你，YQ。
Thank you for giving us the insight and suggestions on using AI agents on Ethereum.
感谢您为我们提供有关在以太坊上使用人工智能代理的见解和建议。
Moving forward, Joseph Schallen, CEO of SharpLink, will have a conversation with Henry Chen, CBO of SNZ.
接下来，SharpLink 首席执行官 Joseph Schallen 将与 SNZ 首席财务官 Henry Chen 进行对话。
Please welcome Joseph and Henry.
请欢迎约瑟夫和亨利。
Thank you, Joseph. Thanks, everyone, for participating in the afternoon.
谢谢你，约瑟夫。谢谢大家下午的参与。
My name is Henry Chen. I'm the CBO of SNZ.
我叫亨利·陈。我是 SNZ 的 CBO。
Very happy to host the Fireside Chat together with Joseph Schallen, CEO of SharpLink.
很高兴与 SharpLink 首席执行官 Joseph Schallen 一起主持炉边谈话。
Joseph, we are at the application panel, and I notice you have your jeans on.
约瑟夫，我们在申请小组，我注意到你穿着牛仔裤。
Very suitable for a session.
非常适合聚会。
I also see you have been on the stage for the third time of this week during the Web3 festivals.
我还看到您本周第三次在 Web3 节日期间登上舞台。
How do you feel so far?
到目前为止你感觉怎么样？
I feel great. First of all, welcome, and thank you for having me.
我感觉很棒。首先，欢迎并感谢您邀请我。
I'm Joseph Schallen, CEO of SharpLink.
我是 Joseph Schallen，SharpLink 的首席执行官。
I'll tell you about SharpLink in a minute, but this is my third time in Hong Kong in the last five months.
我稍后会向您介绍 SharpLink，但这是我在过去五个月内第三次来到香港。
I keep on coming back because I think it has properties that are very different than many other places I travel to.
我不断回来，因为我认为它的属性与我去过的许多其他地方非常不同。
If it's okay, later in this talk, I'll share what they are.
如果可以的话，在本次演讲的稍后部分，我将分享它们是什么。
SharpLink is the first digital asset treasury not on Bitcoin.
SharpLink 是第一个不基于比特币的数字资产库。
Our treasury reserve asset is Ether.
我们的国库储备资产是以太币。
We launched last June. We're listed on the US Nasdaq exchange.
我们于去年六月推出。我们在美国纳斯达克交易所上市。
Today, we own about US$2 billion of Ether, and we make it incredibly productive in the Ethereum ecosystem.
如今，我们拥有约 20 亿美元的以太币，并且我们使其在以太坊生态系统中变得异常高效。
I'm really pleased to be here with you, Henry.
我真的很高兴能和你在一起，亨利。
Thank you. Likewise, happy to see you again here.
谢谢。同样，很高兴在这里再次见到您。
You mentioned it's the third time for five months.
你提到这是五个月来的第三次。
What brings you to Hong Kong?
是什么让你来到香港？
Why do you come so often as the team, I understand, actually out of the United States?
据我所知，为什么你的团队来得如此频繁，实际上是从美国来的？
Sure. If I can be very honest, in the beginning, the first trip was on a world tour,
当然。老实说，一开始，第一次旅行是世界巡演，
spending time in Tokyo and Seoul and Singapore and Hong Kong.
在东京、首尔、新加坡和香港度过时光。
Initially, I thought I was coming to Hong Kong because of the density of capital.
最初，我以为我来香港是因为资本密集。
It was a great place to meet investors, both retail and institutional.
这是结识散户和机构投资者的好地方。
What was shocking, and what brings me back for the second and third time,
是什么让我震惊，是什么让我第二次、第三次回来，
is not just the concentration of capital.
不仅仅是资本的集中。
It is the concentration of talent.
这是人才的集中。
That talent is in the Ethereum ecosystem and the AI ecosystem,
这些人才在以太坊生态系统和人工智能生态系统中，
combined with something that's missing in this world, and that is stability.
加上这个世界上缺少的东西，那就是稳定性。
If you're building businesses, if you're investing,
如果你在创业，如果你在投资，
you want a region that has a stable environment with very clear regulation,
你想要一个拥有稳定环境和非常明确监管的地区，
and Hong Kong certainly offers us that.
香港确实为我们提供了这一点。
That's why it's a very attractive place to build, to invest, and attract talent.
这就是为什么它是一个非常有吸引力的建设、投资和吸引人才的地方。
You mentioned the regulation, but we're going to come back to that point in a minute.
您提到了法规，但我们稍后会回到这一点。
Maybe for some of the audience who don't know your background,
也许对于一些不了解你背景的观众来说，
may I maybe share with you a bit more insight?
我可以与您分享更多见解吗？
You spent two decades at BlackRock,
你在贝莱德工作了二十年，
driving and leading the development of the digital asset initiatives
推动和领导数字资产计划的发展
and the FinTech initiatives of BlackRock, and then you retired.
以及贝莱德的金融科技计划，然后你就退休了。
Then you came back from retirement for Ethereum.
然后你退休后又回到以太坊。
What made you make that decision?
是什么让你做出这个决定？
For the people in the audience who are not aware,
对于不知情的观众来说，
BlackRock is a US-based asset manager, but it's global.
贝莱德是一家总部位于美国的资产管理公司，但它是全球性的。
It manages over $14 trillion of assets around the globe.
它在全球管理着超过 14 万亿美元的资产。
It is the largest manager of money globally.
它是全球最大的资金管理公司。
For most of my career there, thank you for reminding me that I'm old.
在我职业生涯的大部分时间里，谢谢你提醒我我已经老了。
For most of my career, I helped a team scale a FinTech platform called Aladdin.
在我职业生涯的大部分时间里，我帮助一个团队扩展了一个名为 Aladdin 的金融科技平台。
You can think of it as the largest enterprise portfolio management,
你可以把它看作是最大的企业组合管理，
trading, and risk management platform for investors on the buy side.
买方投资者的交易和风险管理平台。
It actually gave me a front row seat on how the market structure globally was working.
它实际上让我了解了全球市场结构的运作方式。
We'll come back to that.
我们稍后会回来讨论这一点。
The last six years at BlackRock, I was lucky enough to lead a very small,
在贝莱德的过去六年里，我很幸运能够领导一个非常小的、
but a very talented team who had the idea that BlackRock can play a leadership role
但这是一个非常有才华的团队，他们认为贝莱德可以发挥领导作用
in changing how traditional financial players viewed crypto
改变传统金融参与者对加密货币的看法
and how the crypto digital asset community understood traditional investors.
以及加密数字资产社区如何理解传统投资者。
We did that in a few ways.
我们通过几种方式做到了这一点。
We became the manager of the USDC Circle Reserve,
我们成为 USDC Circle Reserve 的管理者，
all the treasuries that backed the second largest stablecoin,
所有支持第二大稳定币的财政部，
to learn how money is going to move in the future,
了解未来资金将如何流动，
both for consumers and for institutions and in agentic.
对于消费者、机构和代理商来说。
The second is we built the largest crypto products in history.
第二是我们构建了历史上最大的加密产品。
We launched ETFs for Bitcoin and ETH in 2024,
我们于 2024 年推出了比特币和 ETH ETF，
and humbly, they were the fastest growing financial products in history.
谦虚地说，它们是历史上增长最快的金融产品。
We raised about $100 billion in a couple of years.
我们在几年内筹集了约 1000 亿美元。
That's not because we had the greatest ideas,
这并不是因为我们有最伟大的想法，
but there was significant demand from both retail and institutions,
但零售和机构都有大量需求，
not just in the U.S. but globally, to own Bitcoin and ETH in their portfolios,
不仅在美国，而且在全球范围内，在他们的投资组合中拥有比特币和以太坊，
and they liked owning it through a traditional exchange product.
他们喜欢通过传统的交换产品来拥有它。
And then finally, we believe that tokenization of real world assets,
最后，我们相信现实世界资产的代币化，
stocks, bonds, funds, real estates, commodities,
股票、债券、基金、房地产、大宗商品、
are going to fundamentally bring in a new era of finance,
将从根本上引入一个新的金融时代，
an era of on-chain digital finance,
链上数字金融时代，
and an agentic finance that we've never seen before.
以及我们以前从未见过的代理金融。
So we invested in the ecosystem,
所以我们投资了生态系统，
and we tokenized a yield-bearing fund on Ethereum
我们在以太坊上代币化了一个收益基金
that became the largest tokenized fund in history,
成为历史上最大的代币化基金，
almost $3 billion on-chain to provide yield to people who wanted to stay on-chain,
近 30 亿美元的链上资金为那些想留在链上的人提供收益，
but didn't want to sacrifice losing yield.
但又不想牺牲产量损失。
So it was a great journey.
所以这是一次很棒的旅程。
That was a really long answer.
这是一个非常长的答案。
I retired for six weeks, but I believe very strongly,
我退休了六周，但我坚信，
from the bottom of my heart,
我从心底里，
that Ethereum is going to be the future decentralized, programmable, 24-7 chain,
以太坊将成为未来去中心化、可编程、24-7 的链，
not the only chain in the world,
不是世界上唯一的连锁店，
but it will be the chain that runs the future of capital markets.
但这将是运行资本市场未来的链条。
And SharpLink, which was the first digital asset treasury,
SharpLink是第一个数字资产金库，
was built to give investors access to that future opportunity,
旨在让投资者获得未来的机会，
to own our stock, which gives you access to Ether and its performance,
拥有我们的股票，这使您可以访问以太币及其性能，
and to make Ether as productive as possible in the ecosystem
并使以太币在生态系统中尽可能高效
through staking and other yield generation activities.
通过质押和其他收益产生活动。
So it has been an incredibly fun journey.
所以这是一次非常有趣的旅程。
I've never had more fun than watching the pace of change here in Hong Kong
我从来没有比观看香港的变化步伐更有趣的了
and the pace of change that's coming to Asia.
以及亚洲即将发生的变革步伐。
While it's being led in the U.S.,
虽然它是在美国主导的，
Hong Kong is a fast follower
香港是快速追随者
and has all the characteristics to be the digital leader in all of Asia.
并具备成为全亚洲数字领导者的所有特征。
Well, I certainly heard a lot of passion and excitement
嗯，我当然听到了很多激情和兴奋
when you talk about the application in Hong Kong.
当你谈论在香港的申请时。
I want to come back to the regulation.
我想回到监管。
Actually, there was a big regulatory progress or policy coming out just two weeks ago.
事实上，就在两周前，监管方面已经取得了重大进展或政策出台。
The HKMA, the Hong Kong Central Bank,
金管局、香港中央银行、
actually issued two licenses on stablecoin to two issuers.
实际上向两个发行人颁发了两个稳定币许可证。
And I understand SharpLink has been trying to focus a lot on payment aspects
我知道 SharpLink 一直在努力关注支付方面
empowered by stablecoin,
由稳定币赋能，
and previously Blackcore worked very closely with one of the earliest stablecoin issuers.
此前 Blackcore 与最早的稳定币发行人之一密切合作。
Could you maybe share a bit more on the stablecoin side
您能否分享更多关于稳定币方面的信息
and also touch on the regulatory difference or similarity between Hong Kong and the U.S.?
and also touch on the regulatory difference or similarity between Hong Kong and the U.S.?
Well, first of all, congratulations.
嗯，首先，恭喜你。
And there's a reason why I say congratulations,
And there's a reason why I say congratulations,
because there are a lot of other regions who haven't yet figured out
因为还有很多其他地区还没弄清楚
that stablecoins, regulated stablecoins run by sophisticated institutions with risk management,
that stablecoins, regulated stablecoins run by sophisticated institutions with risk management,
is the first building block.
是第一个构建块。
It's a prerequisite.
这是一个先决条件。
It's a requirement for the future of a digital economy.
这是数字经济未来的要求。
Payments are not going to happen using Hong Kong dollars or fiat.
付款不会使用港元或法定货币。
They're going to happen through a digital Hong Kong dollar.
它们将通过数字港元来实现。
And it's not just to move tokenized assets.
这不仅仅是转移代币化资产。
Many listed companies are going to adopt stablecoins to move cash,
许多上市公司将采用稳定币来转移现金，
to move treasury assets in an instant, not to wait a day.
立即转移库存资产，而不是等待一天。
And you're going to start seeing cross-border commerce,
你将开始看到跨境贸易，
so commercial activities leveraging the Hong Kong dollar stablecoin.
因此商业活动利用港元稳定币。
And I think in the long run, when there is an ability to tokenize assets,
我认为从长远来看，当有能力将资产代币化时，
whether it's stocks on the Hong Kong exchange or real estate or other assets,
无论是香港交易所的股票还是房地产或其他资产，
the means of distribution and payment is going to be on Ethereum,
分配和支付方式将在以太坊上进行，
but the movement of value is going to happen using stablecoins.
但价值的转移将通过稳定币来实现。
So you can think of it as the first building block for a future digital economy.
因此，您可以将其视为未来数字经济的第一个基石。
So I actually congratulate the HKMA to Duncan,
所以我实际上向邓肯表示祝贺金管局，
who's been a leader in your legislator, and Oasis,
谁是你们的立法者和绿洲组织的领导人
the arm of the government who's interested in promoting technology and innovation.
致力于促进技术和创新的政府部门。
They're doing it safely, but this is just the beginning.
他们做得很安全，但这只是开始。
It is not the end of the regulation that's necessary
监管的结束并不是必要的
to make Hong Kong a leader in Asia for digital commerce.
使香港成为亚洲数码商务的领导者。
Thank you, thank you.
谢谢，谢谢。
And coming back to SharpLink, for the past four months,
回到 SharpLink，在过去的四个月里，
SharpLink has been focusing on the digital asset strategies,
SharpLink一直专注于数字资产策略，
digital asset treasury strategies for Ethereum.
以太坊的数字资产金库策略。
And for the public, they've seen, and SharpLink is the first one to do so,
对于公众来说，他们已经看到了，SharpLink 是第一个这样做的，
I would like to focus, emphasize.
我想强调，强调。
Can you maybe share with the public, with the audience,
你能否与公众、与观众分享，
what differentiates SharpLink from other digital asset companies or DAT companies,
SharpLink 与其他数字资产公司或 DAT 公司的区别是什么，
in particular for the DAT companies in Ethereum ecosystem?
特别是对于以太坊生态系统中的 DAT 公司？
Sure. So for audience members who are not aware,
当然。那么对于不知情的观众来说，
the first digital asset treasury was built by a gentleman named Michael Saylor.
第一个数字资产金库是由一位名叫 Michael Saylor 的绅士建立的。
He built a company called MicroStrategy. Today it's called Strategy.
他创办了一家名为 MicroStrategy 的公司。今天它被称为战略。
And he had the idea that if investors wanted to access Bitcoin,
他的想法是，如果投资者想获得比特币，
many struggled to own the spot Bitcoin themselves,
许多人努力自己拥有现货比特币，
set up a wallet, do their own custody.
设立钱包，自己保管。
So he built a public company as a treasury,
所以他建立了一家上市公司作为财务部门，
so he would buy the Bitcoin and you would buy his equity.
所以他会购买比特币，你会购买他的股权。
Ethereum is actually a much better digital asset treasury product.
以太坊实际上是一个更好的数字资产理财产品。
The reason is Bitcoin is a store of value.
原因是比特币是一种价值储存手段。
You own it, you hold it, and you hope it goes up in value,
你拥有它，你持有它，你希望它升值，
it goes down in value, it continues to grow.
它的价值会下降，但会继续增长。
Ethereum has a property just like Bitcoin where it stores value,
以太坊拥有像比特币一样的属性，可以存储价值，
but it also is the future network,
但这也是未来的网络，
and Ether, the token, is what's securing trillions of dollars of value.
而以太币，即代币，则保证了数万亿美元的价值。
But the final difference, and it's really critical to listen to,
但最后的区别，听听真的很重要，
is Ether can generate yield, meaning you can own your Ether tokens,
以太币可以产生收益，这意味着你可以拥有你的以太币，
hold it for capital appreciation,
持有它是为了资本增值，
but Ether, if you stake it in the ecosystem to secure transactions,
但是以太币，如果你将其放入生态系统中以确保交易安全，
you can earn almost 3% yield beyond just holding the asset.
除了持有资产之外，您还可以获得近 3% 的收益率。
At SharpLink, we are completely differentiated from Bitcoin debts
在 SharpLink，我们与比特币债务完全不同
and even from our Ethereum competitors in that we were the first
甚至来自我们的以太坊竞争对手，因为我们是第一个
to stake nearly 100% of the Ether to generate Ethereum rewards,
质押近 100% 的以太币来产生以太坊奖励，
which shows up on our balance sheet as revenue for our investors.
这在我们的资产负债表上显示为投资者的收入。
Second is we have something that's very hard to find in this room.
其次，我们在这个房间里有一些很难找到的东西。
It's very hard to find in the crypto industry.
在加密行业很难找到。
It's what we call permanent capital.
这就是我们所说的永久资本。
We own our Ether for a generation.
我们拥有一代人的以太币。
We don't have to sell it like an ETF,
我们不必像 ETF 那样出售它，
which means we can take our Ether, go out into the Ethereum protocol community,
这意味着我们可以带着以太币进入以太坊协议社区，
and make it available for staking and restaking in massive scale.
并使其可用于大规模质押和重新质押。
And when we do that, very often we're able to get incentives,
当我们这样做时，我们常常能够获得激励，
higher returns than the average Ethereum staker,
比普通以太坊质押者获得更高的回报，
and we do that for the benefit of our investors.
我们这样做是为了投资者的利益。
So we're one of the largest treasuries in the world.
所以我们是世界上最大的金库之一。
We own $2 billion of ETH,
我们拥有 20 亿美元的 ETH，
and we have an institutional team who knows how to get additional yield
我们有一个知道如何获得额外收益的机构团队
while keeping the risk within an institutional framework.
同时将风险控制在制度框架内。
And we're quite proud to keep coming back to Hong Kong
我们很自豪能够继续回到香港
because I think Ethereum here is a leading development platform.
因为我认为以太坊是一个领先的开发平台。
It's a builder community,
这是一个建设者社区，
and I'd love to share later what I saw yesterday,
我很乐意稍后分享我昨天所看到的，
which made me so excited in West Kowloon.
这让我在西九龙很兴奋。
All right, thank you.
好的，谢谢。
Maybe, since you mentioned that,
也许，既然你提到了这一点，
let's maybe talk about what has been taking place during your recent trips,
我们也许可以谈谈你最近旅行期间发生的事情，
especially for the past few days.
尤其是最近几天。
I know you attended a very big event related to the Ethereum community,
我知道你参加了一个与以太坊社区相关的大型活动，
and you spent a full day there.
你在那里度过了一整天。
Very busy, but hopefully very rewarding.
很忙，但希望很有收获。
So could you share with the public who wasn't there,
那么你能和不在场的公众分享一下吗？
what was happening, and how did you see the crowds and the community?
发生了什么事？您如何看待人群和社区？
Sure. Ethereum has a special connection to China and Hong Kong.
当然。以太坊与中国和香港有着特殊的联系。
You'll hear later today around 4 or 4.30 from Vitalik Buterin,
今天晚些时候，您会在 4 点或 4.30 左右听到 Vitalik Buterin 发来的消息：
who is the founder of Ethereum.
谁是以太坊的创始人。
The founder of Ethereum.
以太坊创始人。
And Dr. Xiao from Hashkey will be interviewing him.
Hashkey的肖博士将采访他。
They had deep roots in Shanghai.
他们在上海有着深厚的根基。
You'll hear Vitalik speak not in my broken English,
你会听到维塔利克说的不是我蹩脚的英语，
but in pretty good Mandarin.
但普通话说得很好。
And what's really special is because of that history,
真正特别的是因为那段历史
there are community builders and contributors to the Ethereum ecosystem.
以太坊生态系统有社区建设者和贡献者。
But yesterday was a remarkable and I would say a noteworthy and special day.
但昨天是一个非凡的日子，我想说这是一个值得注意和特别的日子。
In collaboration with SNZ and with the Ethereum Foundation,
与 SNZ 和以太坊基金会合作，
and I commend Aya as the president, I commend Gilles and SNZ,
我赞扬 Aya 作为主席，我赞扬 Gilles 和 SNZ，
they built in West Kowloon the first Ethereum community hub in Asia,
他们在西九龙建立了亚洲第一个以太坊社区中心，
and they chose Hong Kong specifically.
他们特别选择了香港。
And it's going to house builders not just of core Ethereum protocols,
它不仅会为核心以太坊协议的构建者提供住所，
applications, AI-related capabilities, quantum-proof applications,
应用程序、人工智能相关功能、量子证明应用程序、
and most importantly, they're going to build things that we can't even imagine today.
最重要的是，他们将建造我们今天无法想象的东西。
And what's important about this is Ethereum was built
重要的是以太坊的建立
not as a centralized marketing organization,
不是作为一个集中的营销组织，
not as a locked-in vendor chain like many of the others.
不像其他许多供应商链那样是一个锁定的供应商链。
Ethereum was built through ongoing contributions of the community
以太坊是通过社区的持续贡献而建立的
with Hong Kong and Shanghai being at the roots, the hearts, and the centers.
以香港和上海为根、心和中心。
So I'm really, really excited.
所以我真的非常非常兴奋。
Vitalik spoke yesterday of this idea that there's going to be a new way
维塔利克昨天谈到了这个想法，即将会有一种新的方式
that code will be built.
该代码将被构建。
Code will be built in a way that will find bugs,
代码将以能够发现错误的方式构建，
because if you don't, the large language models will find them for you.
因为如果您不这样做，大型语言模型将为您找到它们。
And Ethereum was built initially as a tower of capabilities,
以太坊最初是作为一座能力之塔而建立的，
but over the next few years, Ethereum will be rebuilt from scratch with new capabilities,
但在接下来的几年里，以太坊将通过新功能从头开始重建，
not adding floors to a tower or skyscraper,
不增加塔楼或摩天大楼的楼层，
but reimagining it every few years because the pace of technology is changing.
但每隔几年就会重新设想一次，因为技术的步伐在不断变化。
So even though it's just a building,
所以尽管它只是一栋建筑
it will be a sacred place where builders and innovators can be mentored,
它将成为建设者和创新者可以得到指导的神圣场所，
can be invested in, and can meet the institutional community.
可以投资并可以与机构群体见面。
So I found it to be a remarkable day.
所以我发现这是非凡的一天。
The first time the Ethereum Foundation built a hub for the future,
以太坊基金会第一次为未来建立了一个中心，
and they chose Hong Kong.
他们选择了香港。
And I think it was intentional.
我认为这是故意的。
That's great to hear.
很高兴听到这个消息。
And I think there are two keywords that repeatedly was mentioned in your notes so far.
我认为到目前为止，您的笔记中反复提到了两个关键字。
One is builder, one is application.
一种是构建者，一种是应用程序。
As a leader of SharpLink and together with actually the co-founder of Ethereum,
作为 SharpLink 的领导者以及以太坊的联合创始人，
Joe Lubin, as a chairman on the board,
乔·鲁宾 (Joe Lubin) 作为董事会主席，
how do you see SharpLink progress in the future,
您如何看待 SharpLink 未来的进展，
you know, starting with a debt company,
你知道，从一家债务公司开始，
but how would you focus on what applications and ecosystem for Ethereum in the future?
但未来你会如何关注以太坊的哪些应用和生态系统呢？
Sure. For those of you who don't know consensus,
当然。对于那些不知道共识的人来说，
Joe Lubin, my chairman, is a co-founder of Ethereum alongside Vitalik and several others.
我的董事长 Joe Lubin 是以太坊的联合创始人，与 Vitalik 和其他几位成员一起。
And when Ethereum was being built, somebody had to build the applications,
当以太坊被构建时，必须有人构建应用程序，
the wallets, the developer tools.
钱包、开发者工具。
So Joe Lubin built a company called Consensus.
于是 Joe Lubin 成立了一家名为 Consensus 的公司。
It is the owner of Metamask, one of the most widely used Web3 wallets in the world today.
它是 Metamask 的所有者，Metamask 是当今世界上使用最广泛的 Web3 钱包之一。
And what that gives us is access directly to the newest protocols,
这让我们可以直接访问最新的协议，
to the most innovative builders, and as an Ethereum capital holder,
致最具创新精神的建设者，以及作为以太坊资本持有者，
billions of dollars of Ether, we kind of have a first look,
数十亿美元的以太币，我们先看看，
a first opportunity, not only to stake our ETH,
第一次机会，不仅是质押我们的 ETH，
but to invest into these communities for profit,
但要投资这些社区以获取利润，
to invest in these protocols, not for short-term yield harvesting,
投资这些协议，而不是为了短期收益收获，
but to invest in these communities to give them their initial capital,
而是投资这些社区，为他们提供初始资本，
to give them that ability to start and attract new capital,
赋予他们启动和吸引新资本的能力，
and that is part of our mandate, because what's good for Ethereum is good for Ether
这是我们使命的一部分，因为对以太坊有利的事情对以太坊也有利
and is good for SharpLink.
对 SharpLink 有好处。
So we think we clearly have a for-profit model,
所以我们认为我们显然有一个营利模式，
but we have a responsibility to give back, and being part of Consensus is incredibly powerful.
但我们有责任回馈社会，成为共识的一部分是非常强大的。
But beyond being a treasury, we're going to continue to accumulate Ether
但除了作为金库之外，我们还将继续积累以太币
until we hold about 5% of the Ethereum pool.
直到我们持有大约 5% 的以太坊池。
We've grown about 0.7% today.
今天我们增长了约 0.7%。
But over time, we'll build operating businesses that are aligned with the Ethereum ecosystem
但随着时间的推移，我们将建立与以太坊生态系统相一致的运营业务
and hopefully spin off Ethereum-denominated returns and revenue,
并希望分拆以以太坊计价的回报和收入，
which will be another way to accumulate Ether on our balance sheet.
这将是在我们的资产负债表上积累以太币的另一种方式。
So it's quite exciting.
所以这非常令人兴奋。
The last thing I'll say on this topic is people are too focused on the price of Bitcoin and ETH and Solana.
关于这个话题我要说的最后一件事是人们过于关注比特币、ETH 和 Solana 的价格。
The best time to build is when you're at a low.
构建的最佳时机是当你处于低谷时。
You can find the best talent. You can really innovate.
您可以找到最优秀的人才。你真的可以创新。
So at moments of drawdowns and consolidations, that is the time to lean in and build,
因此，在缩减和整合的时刻，是时候依靠和建设，
not to get scared, but to actually find the opportunities.
不是害怕，而是真正找到机会。
Retail is scared right now of the price of crypto,
零售业现在对加密货币的价格感到害怕，
but institutions are piling in like we've never seen before.
但机构正以前所未有的方式涌入。
That's great. What advice would you give to the founders and builders,
那太棒了。您会给创始人和建设者什么建议？
especially when they're building applications, payment?
特别是当他们构建应用程序时，付款？
Off the stadium, you actually shared a lot of points on agentics, for example.
例如，在球场外，您实际上分享了很多有关代理的观点。
Is there anything you can share with the audience today?
今天您有什么可以跟观众分享的吗？
Sure. So I come from a culture where respect for elders was really, really important.
当然。所以我来自一种尊重长辈非常非常重要的文化。
In my culture, my parents came first, my grandparents came first,
在我的文化中，我的父母是第一位的，我的祖父母是第一位的，
and we were obedient. You know, we followed rules.
我们很听话。你知道，我们遵守规则。
But I said a message yesterday at the Ethereum Community Hub,
但我昨天在以太坊社区中心说了一条消息，
and I hope it's conveyed properly in Chinese.
我希望它能用中文正确传达。
I would ask builders and innovators, whether it's Ethereum or AI or agentic,
我会问建设者和创新者，无论是以太坊、人工智能还是代理，
to be respectfully disobedient.
恭敬地不服从。
Respectfully disobedient.
恭敬不顺。
Respect the principles of honesty and decentralization and long-term thinking
尊重诚实、放权和长远思考的原则
and building with privacy first and security first.
并以隐私第一和安全第一为原则进行建设。
Respect the principles, but be disobedient.
尊重原则，但不服从。
Don't build on top of the tower that was built before.
不要在以前建造的塔顶上建造。
Don't build the same type of applications in an incremental manner.
不要以增量方式构建相同类型的应用程序。
Imagine that if you were starting to build a tower from scratch,
想象一下，如果你从头开始建造一座塔，
how would you build it today?
今天你会如何建造它？
And even Vitalik will say, there is nothing sacred about the current stack.
甚至 Vitalik 也会说，当前堆栈没有什么神圣之处。
Rebuild it. Re-innovate.
重建它。重新创新。
So be respectful of the principles,
所以要尊重原则，
but be disobedient in following what we've built today.
但不服从我们今天所建立的东西。
That is at the crux of innovation.
这是创新的关键。
And I think agentic, we heard from a previous speaker a lot of the technical elements,
我认为代理，我们从之前的演讲者那里听到了很多技术元素，
but I'd love to speak about the vision of what agentic is going to look like,
但我很想谈谈 Agentic 的愿景，
because I think most people, humans underestimate how big the change that's coming,
因为我认为大多数人低估了即将发生的变化有多大
not in a decade, but in this year and next in our lives on agentic.
不是十年后，而是今年和明年我们的生活中。
Yes. Actually, do you want to expand on the agentic payment part, for example?
是的。实际上，例如您想扩展代理支付部分吗？
Given actually consensus was the parent code of Metamask,
鉴于实际上共识是 Metamask 的父代码，
and Metamask was the first most broadly adopted DeFi wallet,
Metamask 是第一个最广泛采用的 DeFi 钱包，
which DeFi is actually the infrastructure to support the future agentic economy in my mind.
其中 DeFi 其实是我心目中支撑未来代理经济的基础设施。
So can you maybe expand on that?
那么你可以扩展一下吗？
I will, but can I give you a global macro-historical view?
我会的，但是我能给你一个全球宏观历史观吗？
To the young people in the room, or even the middle-aged in the room,
对在场的年轻人，甚至在场的中年人来说，
most generations, most centuries see one, maybe two innovations
大多数世代、大多数世纪都会看到一种、也许两种创新
that fundamentally change society and how people live.
从根本上改变社会和人们的生活方式。
It was the railroad, it was the steam engine, it was the telegraph,
这是铁路，这是蒸汽机，这是电报，
it was the automated assembly line, and it was the internet in the 90s.
那是自动化装配线，那是 90 年代的互联网。
Usually there's one mega-force that you see in a generation,
通常你会在一代人的时间里看到一股巨大的力量，
and it changes how people exchange information, how people build,
它改变了人们交换信息的方式，人们建造的方式，
how people communicate with one another, and how people pay each other.
人们如何相互沟通，以及人们如何相互支付。
We are lucky and grateful to live through a time
我们很幸运也很感激能够度过一段时光
where there are four or five mega-forces colliding and converging in this very moment.
此刻，有四五股巨力碰撞汇聚。
For young people, this doesn't happen in our lifetimes.
对于年轻人来说，这在我们的有生之年是不会发生的。
Let me tell you what they are.
让我告诉你它们是什么。
There is the greatest transfer of wealth from grandparents to children and grandchildren
最大的财富转移是从祖父母到子孙
that we've ever seen in human history.
这是我们在人类历史上所见过的。
In every region around the world, the aging are going to pass
在世界各地，老龄化将会过去
tens and tens of trillions of dollars of assets.
数十万亿美元的资产。
It's not going to people who go to physical banks.
去实体银行的人不会这么做。
They don't trust advisors, they trust code, and they trust their phones.
他们不信任顾问，他们信任代码，并且信任他们的手机。
How many of you in the room use AI on a daily basis?
在座有多少人每天都使用人工智能？
Almost everyone.
几乎每个人。